

#### Ph.D. Student at Georgia Tech

iunmo.kang@gatech.edu
 im-kang.github.io

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

#### NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING (NLP)

LARGE LANGUAGE MODELS, INSTRUCTION-BASED LEARNING, RETRIEVAL-AUGMENTATION, EFFICIENT NLP, ROBUSTNESS

The long-term goal of my research is to enhance the *practicality* of NLP systems (e.g., Large Language Models), promoting their widespread use in real-world scenarios. In particular, my research focuses on i) how to make NLP models more efficient in terms of data, parameters, or compute, and ii) how to build NLP models that are robust to unseen cases in the wild.

#### EDUCATION \_\_\_\_

#### GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Atlanta, GA, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Research Assistant at NLP Lab (Advisor: Alan Ritter, Wei Xu)
- GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

## KOREA ADVANCED INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Feb. 2021

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Research Assistant at IR&NLP Lab (Advisor: Sung-Hyon Myaeng)
- Thesis committee: Sung-Hyong Myaeng, Hojin Choi, Alice Oh
- GPA: 4.03 / 4.30

#### CHUNGNAM NATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Feb. 2019

- B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING
  - · Summa Cum Laude
  - GPA: 4.30 / 4.50 (Rank: 1/125 in CSE, Major GPA: 4.41)

## PUBLICATIONS \_\_\_\_

- \* indicates equal contribution
- [1] Self-Specialization: Uncovering Latent Expertise within Large Language Models Preprint Junmo Kang, Hongyin Luo, Yada Zhu, James Glass, David Cox, Alan Ritter, Rogerio Feris, Leonid Karlinsky [pdf]
- [2] Schema-Driven Information Extraction from Heterogeneous Tables Fan Bai, Junmo Kang, Gabriel Stanovsky, Dayne Freitag, Alan Ritter [pdf]

Preprint

[3] Discern and Answer: Mitigating the Impact of Misinformation in Retrieval-Augmented Models with Discriminators Preprint

Giwon Hong\*, Jeonghwan Kim\*, Junmo Kang\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng, Joyce Jiyoung Whang [pdf]

[4] Distill or Annotate? Cost-Efficient Fine-Tuning of Compact Models Junmo Kang, Wei Xu, Alan Ritter [pdf]

ACL 2023

[5] Graph-Induced Transformers for Efficient Multi-Hop Question Answering Giwon Hong, Jeonghwan Kim, Junmo Kang, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

**EMNLP 2022** 

- [6] Exploiting Numerical-Contextual Knowledge to Improve Numerical Reasoning in Question Answering
  Findings of NAACL 2022

  Jeonghwan Kim, Junmo Kang, Giwon Hong, Kyung-min Kim, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [7] Ultra-High Dimensional Sparse Representations with Binarization for Efficient Text Retrieval EMNLP 2021

Kyoung-Rok Jang, Junmo Kang, Giwon Hong, Sung-Hyon Myaeng, Joohee Park, Taewon Yoon, Heecheol Seo [pdf]

[8] Leveraging Order-Free Tag Relations for Context-Aware Recommendation Junmo Kang, Jeonghwan Kim, Suwon Shin, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

**EMNLP 2021** 

- [9] Have You Seen That Number? Investigating Extrapolation in Question Answering Models EMNLP 2021 Jeonghwan Kim, Giwon Hong, Kyung-min Kim, Junmo Kang, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [10] Can You Distinguish Truthful from Fake Reviews? User Analysis and Assistance Tool for Fake Review Detection

  HCI+NLP@EACL 2021

  Jeonghwan Kim\*, Junmo Kang\*, Suwon Shin\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [11] Regularization of Distinct Strategies for Unsupervised Question Generation

  Junmo Kang\*, Giwon Hong\*, Haritz Puerto San Roman\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

  Findings of EMNLP 2020
- [12] Handling Anomalies of Synthetic Questions in Unsupervised Question Answering
  Giwon Hong\*, Junmo Kang\*, Doyeon Lim\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [13] Let Me Know What to Ask: Interrogative-Word-Aware Question Generation

  Junmo Kang\*, Haritz Puerto San Roman\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

MRQA@EMNLP 2019

#### **EXPERIENCES**

MIT-IBM WATSON AI LAB Cambridge, MA, USA

Research Intern (Host: Leonid Karlinsky, Rogerio Feris)

May. 2023 - Aug. 2023

• Self-alignment of large language models for specialization [1].

GEORGIA TECH Atlanta, GA, USA

Graduate Research Assistant (Advisor: Alan Ritter, Wei Xu)

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Instructing LLMs with schema for efficient and robust table extraction [2].
- Cost-efficiency of annotation and distillation [4].

KAIST IR&NLP LAB Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Research Associate (Host: Sung-Hyon Myaeng)

Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- Instruction-based learning for robust retrieval-augmented LLMs [3].
- Efficient methods for multi-hop QA [5].

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Assistant (Advisor: Sung-Hyon Myaeng)

Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Question generation and unsupervised question answering for data-efficiency [11,12,13].
- Sample-efficient and robust representations for numerical reasoning [9,6].
- Generative model that leverages inter-dependency of tags while alleviating the order sensitivity [8].
- Sparse representations for passage retrieval that can take advantage of an efficient inverted index and symbolic IR techniques [7].

# HONORS & AWARDS \_\_\_\_\_

Graduated with Highest Honor in CSE, Chungnam National University	2019
Grand Prize, Business ICT Competition	2018
Excellence Award, Startup Competition	2018
Finalist, NAVER AI Hackathon	2018
Grand Prize, Daejeon Startup School	2017
Best Excellence Award, Startup Picnic	2016
Finalist, Microsoft Imagine Cup Korea	2016